Guide to the Hans Caspar Syz Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Ceramics Files, 1942-1990, undated; Series VI
  - Writings on ceramics
    - "Some oriental aspects of European ceramic decoration"
      - Part III (reprint Antiques, Aug), 1969
        - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 69, Folder 19)
    - "Some oriental aspects of European ceramic decoration" (second edition in Keramik-Freunde der Schweiz Mitteilungsblatt )
      - Reprint, 1970 (Box 69, Folder 20)
      - Additions, 1970 (Box 69, Folder 21)
      - Correspondence and corrections, 1970 (Box 69, Folder 22)
    - Catalogue of the Hans Syz Collection: Vol. I. Meissen porcelain and Hausmalerei
      - Correspondence with collaborator, Rainer Ruckert, 1960-1969 (Box 69, Folder 23-24)
      - Correspondence with collaborator, Rainer Ruckert, 1970-1990 (Box 70, Folder 25-27)
      - Awards given to catalogue, 1980 (Box 70, Folder 28)
      - Reviews of the catalogue, 1980-1982 (Box 70, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence with individuals
    - A-Z, 1965-1977 (Box 70, Folder 30-40)
    - Amman, Max, 1967-1972 (Box 71, Folder 41)
    - Arnhold, Henry H., 1973-1977 (Box 71, Folder 42)
    - Austin, John C., 1969 (Box 71, Folder 43)
    - Avery, C. Louise, 1949-1957 (Box 71, Folder 44)
    - Bailey, B., 1952-1966 (Box 71, Folder 45)
    - Barringer, Lawrence E., 1955-1956 (Box 71, Folder 46)
    - Bayer, Adolf, 1960 (Box 71, Folder 47)
    - Berliner, Rudolf, 1949-1956 (Box 71, Folder 48)
    - Bischoff, Ilse, 1960-1981 (Box 71, Folder 49)
    - Blackburn, William, 1953-1962 (Box 71, Folder 50)
    - Bondi, Roberto, 1956-1971 (Box 71, Folder 51)
    - Bustin, Andrew, 1966-1969 (Box 71, Folder 52)
    - Chellis, Mrs. R. D., 1960-1967 (Box 71, Folder 53)
    - Dauterman, Carl C., 1959-1964 (Box 71, Folder 54)
    - Delhom, M. Mellany, 1971-1972 (Box 71, Folder 55)
    - Dreier, F.A., 1967-1971 (Box 71, Folder 56)
    - Ducret, Dr. Siegfried, 1952-1980 (Box 71, Folder 57-59)
    - Ember, Frieda, 1946-1970 (Box 71, Folder 60)
    - Essberger, Elsa, 1960-1963 (Box 71, Folder 61)
    - Ettinghausen, Richard, 1964-1979 (Box 71, Folder 62)
    - Falkner, Dorothy, 1950-1969 (Box 71, Folder 63)
    - Fukugawa, Tadashi, 1973-1976 (Box 71, Folder 64)
    - Geneva, Ariana, 1965-1971 (Box 71, Folder 65)
    - Gies, 1972-1973 (Box 71, Folder 66)
    - Golodetz, Lionel, 1969-1974 (Box 71, Folder 67)
    - Hackenbroch, Y. [for Untermeyer, I.], 1951-1975 (Box 71, Folder 68)
    - Hawes, Lloyd E., 1965 (Box 71, Folder 69)
    - Hayward, John F., 1950-1955 (Box 71, Folder 70)
    - Heuser, Hans-Jorgen, 1954-1974 (Box 71, Folder 71)
    - Heyne, W., 1965-1966 (Box 71, Folder 72)
    - Impey, Oliver, 1977-1978 (Box 71, Folder 73)
    - Jarchow, Margarete, 1987 (Box 71, Folder 74)
    - Kramer, Ernst, 1959 (Box 72, Folder 75)
    - Krieger, Martin, 1963-1971 (Box 72, Folder 76)
    - Kunze, Magda, 1970 (Box 72, Folder 77)
    - Landman, Hedy Backlin, 1972-1974 (Box 72, Folder 78)
    - Mayer, John, 1963-1965 (Box 72, Folder 79)
    - Mields, Martin, 1969-1978 (Box 72, Folder 80)
    - Neugass, Fritz, 1966 (Box 72, Folder 81)
    - Nishida, Hiroko, 1973-1978 (Box 72, Folder 82)
    - Oberer, Paul, 1947-1952 (Box 72, Folder 83)
    - Oppenheim, Michel, 1960-1963 (Box 72, Folder 84)
    - Pauls, Emil, 1963-1973 (Box 72, Folder 85)
    - Pflueger, Edward M., 1959-1969 (Box 72, Folder 86)
    - Popp, Kuno, 1962-1964 (Box 72, Folder 87)
    - Ross, Marvin C., 1969-1972 (Box 72, Folder 88)
    - Sawyer, Eleanor, 1964-1967 (Box 72, Folder 89)
    - Schneider, Ernst, 1964-1977 (Box 72, Folder 90)
    - Schnyder, Paul, 1948-1973 (Box 72, Folder 91)
    - Schnyder, Rudolf, 1964-1975 (Box 72, Folder 92)
    - Schönberger, Arno, 1962-1964 (Box 72, Folder 93)
    - Scott, G. Ryland, 1960-1963 (Box 72, Folder 94)
    - Seyffarth, Richard, 1959-1971 (Box 72, Folder 95)
    - Shono, Masako, 1969-1985 (Box 72, Folder 96)
    - Stazzi, Francesco, 1963-1970 (Box 72, Folder 97)
    - Steinhauser, Ludwig, 1964 (Box 72, Folder 98)
    - Stout, Warda, 1955-1972 (Box 72, Folder 99)
    - Strasser, Rudolph G., 1962-1983 (Box 72, Folder 100)
    - Tabakoff, Sheila K., 1973-1978 (Box 72, Folder 101)
    - Torre, Andreina, 1970-1982 (Box 72, Folder 102-103)
    - Van Heeckeren van Walien, F. Baron, 1965-1978 (Box 72, Folder 104)
    - Vecht, A., 1965 (Box 72, Folder 105)
    - Viale, Vittorio, 1953-1971 (Box 72, Folder 106)
    - Wark, Ralph, 1953-1984 (Box 73, Folder 107-109)
    - Wilson, R. Thornton, 1954-1960 (Box 73, Folder 110)
    - Wolf, Hans, 1985 (Box 73, Folder 111)
    - Wolfson, Janet M., 1960-1972 (Box 73, Folder 112)
  - Dealer and active factory representatives files
    - General, A-Z (Box 73, Folder 113)
    - Backer, H.E., 1947-1965 (Box 73, Folder 114-115)
    - Bäuml, Fritz, 1956-1969 (Box 73, Folder 116)
    - Becker, I. F., 1965-1966 (Box 73, Folder 117)
    - Beckhardt of New York, 1942-1977 (Box 73, Folder 118)
    - East Germany - Ceramic Experts, 1969-1970 (Box 73, Folder 119)
    - Lautz, William H., 1949-1973 (Box 73, Folder 120)
    - Rosenberg, C. G. and Company, 1948, 1973 (Box 73, Folder 121)
    - Walcha, Otto, 1959-1968 (Box 73, Folder 122)
    - Weinberg, H., 1956-1976 (Box 73, Folder 123)
    - Winifred Williams Antiques, 1958-1969 (Box 73, Folder 124)
  - Museums and institutions files
    - Abegg-Stiftung Bern, 1969 (Box 74, Folder 125)
    - Académie Internationale de la Céramique, 1957 (Box 74, Folder 126)
    - Altertumsmuseum, 1965 (Box 74, Folder 127)
    - American Ceramic Circle, 1971-1981 (Box 74, Folder 128-129)
    - Baltimore Museum of Art, 1951-1970 (Box 74, Folder 130)
    - Bayerisches National Museum, 1950-1973 (Box 74, Folder 131)
    - Bernisches Historiches Museum, 1962-1966 (Box 74, Folder 132)
    - Busch-Reisinger Museum, 1961-1980 (Box 74, Folder 133)
    - C. L. David Collection, 1965 (Box 74, Folder 134)
    - Carnegie Institute, Frick Art Museum, 1971 (Box 74, Folder 135)
    - Cecil Higgins Art Gallery, 1969-1971 (Box 74, Folder 136)
    - Ceramica Stiftung, 1964-1965 (Box 74, Folder 137)
    - Ceramique Internationale Praha, 1962 (Box 74, Folder 138)
    - Chicago Art Institute, 1946-1960 (Box 74, Folder 139)
    - Cooper-Hewitt Museum, 1978 (Box 74, Folder 140)
    - Cooper-Union Museum, 1960-1963 (Box 74, Folder 141)
    - Deutsche Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin, 1965-1969 (Box 74, Folder 142)
    - Doccia Museum, 1966 (Box 74, Folder 143)
    - Fine Arts Museum of San Francisco, 1978-1979 (Box 74, Folder 144)
    - Frankfurt Museum for Kunsthandwerk, 1960-1970 (Box 74, Folder 145)
    - Freer Gallery of Art, 1965-1977 (Box 74, Folder 146)
    - Frick Collection, 1975 (Box 74, Folder 147)
    - High Museum of Art, 1978-1979 (Box 74, Folder 148)
    - Keramik-freunde der Schweiz, 1954-1971 (Box 74, Folder 149-151)
    - Kulturgeschichtliches Museum, Osnabruck, 1973-1974 (Box 74, Folder 152)
    - Kunstgewerbemuseum, Kunsthistoriches Institut, 1961-1980 (Box 74, Folder 153)
    - Kunsthistoriches Institut der Universität Köln [Gisela Zick], 1972-1979 (Box 74, Folder 154)
    - Lighthouse, 1966 (Box 74, Folder 155)
    - M. H. De Young Memorial Museum, 1964-1965 (Box 74, Folder 156)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1969-1972 (Box 74, Folder 157)
    - Mint Museum of Art, 1969-1971 (Box 74, Folder 158)
    - Musée National de Céramique, 1969-1971 (Box 74, Folder 159)
    - Musées Royaux d'Art et d'Histoire, 1965-1969 (Box 74, Folder 160)
    - Museo Civico di Torino, 1971 (Box 74, Folder 161)
    - Museum of the American China Trade, 1973-1974 (Box 74, Folder 162)
    - Museum of Decorative Art (Kunstindustriemuseum), 1965-1966 (Box 74, Folder 163)
    - Museum fur Kunst and Gewerbe, Hamburg, 1957-1971 (Box 74, Folder 164)
    - Osterreichisches Museum fur Angewandte Kunst, 1962-1969 (Box 74, Folder 165)
    - Philadelphia Museum of Art, 1961-1974 (Box 74, Folder 166)
    - Reissmuseum, 1960-1961 (Box 74, Folder 167)
    - Rijk Museum, 1958-1971 (Box 74, Folder 168)
    - Saarland Museum, 1960-1972 (Box 74, Folder 169)
    - Schweiz Landesmuseum Zürich, 1949-1970 (Box 74, Folder 170)
    - Smithsonian Institution
      - General, 1963-1983 (Box 75, Folder 171)
      - Division of Ceramics and Glass [J. Jefferson Miller II and Paul V. Gardner], 1962-1980 (Box 75, Folder 172-188)
      - Documents relating to Syz's honorary fellowship from the Smithsonian Institution, 1956 (Box 76, Folder 189)
      - Correspondence regarding the opening of an exhibit of Syz's ceramic collection at the Smithsonian Institution, 1966 (Box 76, Folder 190)
      - Plans for the arrangement of Ceramics Hall, Smithsonian Institution, 1966 (Box 76, Folder 191)
      - Opening night, 1966 (Box 76, Folder 192)
    - Staatliche Kunstsammlungen Dresden, 1964-1982 (Box 76, Folder 193)
    - Stadt Frankfurt am Main; Der Magistrat Historiches Museum, 1961-1974 (Box 76, Folder 194)
    - Stedelijk Museum, 1957-1964 (Box 76, Folder 195)
    - Tokyo National Museum of Art, 1968-1971 (Box 76, Folder 196)
    - Toledo Museum of Art, 1973 (Box 76, Folder 197)
    - University of Kansas Museum of Art, 1959-1960 (Box 76, Folder 198)
    - Victoria and Albert Museum, 1968-1976 (Box 76, Folder 199)
    - Wadsorth Atheneum, 1947-1964 (Box 76, Folder 200)
    - Winterthur Museum, 1960-1964 (Box 76, Folder 201)
    - Wurttembergisches Landesmuseum, 1958-1971 (Box 76, Folder 202)
    - Yale University Art Gallery, 1953-1966 (Box 76, Folder 203)
- Restricted, Series VII
  Conditions Governing Access
  Materials are restricted for reasons of privacy until June 1, 2026.
  - General Files
    - C-G (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Halverson, Renfred (Box 77, Folder 2-3)
    - G-S (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - Writings and Research Materials
    - "Posttraumatic Loss of Reproductive Memory and its Restoration through Hypnosis and Analysis" [ The Medical Record, October 7], 1936
      - Case history notes
        - Original notes, Circa1921 (Box 77, Folder 5)
        - Case notebooks, Circa 1921 (Box 77, Folder 6-8)
        - Anamaesis, undated (Box 77, Folder 9)
        - Life history [English and German typescripts], Circa 1921 (Box 77, Folder 10-11)
      - Correspondence
        - General, 1921-1936 (Box 77, Folder 12)
        - Family, 1935-1956 (Box 77, Folder 13)
      - Medical information
        - Nageli, Emil: medical notes, Circa 1921 (Box 77, Folder 14)
          Box CF5, Folder 91
        - Medical insurance certificates, Circa 1921 (Box 77, Folder 15)
        - First physical exam, 1921 (Box 77, Folder 16)
        - Psychological observation, 1921 (Box 77, Folder 17)
        - Oversize (Box 79, Folder 91)
      - Writings and presentations
        - Notes, 1935-1940, undated (Box 78, Folder 18-21)
        - Case writeup, undated (Box 78, Folder 22-23)
        - Outlines, 1921-1927, undated (Box 78, Folder 24)
        - Early drafts, Circa 1921 (Box 78, Folder 25)
    - "Socio-individual Principles in Psychopathology" [ The British Journal of Medical Psychology, Vol. X Part IV ], 1930
      - Drafts of presentations, 1936-1938 (Box 78, Folder 26)
      - Case history [notes and materials], 1935-1936, undated (Box 78, Folder 27-28)
- Additional material, circa 1991; Accession 2018-M-005
  - "Experience and Concept: The Notebooks of Hans Syz, M.D.", circa 1991 (Box 80)